Rory Hartong-Redden

June 10, 2024 | Boulder, CO | roryhr@gmail.com | roryhr.com

Summary

Data scientist with eight years of experience spanning analytics, engineering, and science

Tools

Python, Git, Shell, Julia, Elixir SQL, Metabase, Postgres, Spark, Hadoop, S3 AWS, Docker, CircleCI, CI/CD Jupyter Notebooks, PyCharm, ChatGPT **Python Tools:** matplotlib, seaborn, pandas, Flask, scikit-learn, requests, pytest, Conda

Professional Experience

• SyBridge Technologies (Fast Radius)

Technical Manager and Lead Data Scientist

Boulder, CO Aug 2021–May 2024

- Created SQL queries and visualizations in Metabase of training data and prediction errors
- Maintained high-quality code essential for generating revenue supported by a comprehensive test suite and automated Datadog tests to ensure optimal latency and uptime
- Supported R&D initiatives with statistical analysis and visualization of varied data such as accelerometer, temperature readings, and CAD file sizes using Jupyter Notebooks with Python
- Worked with cross-functional teams to align on manufacturing process cost models

• Fast Radius Chicago, IL

Data Scientist Feb 2020-Aug 2021

- Tech stack: Python, scikit-learn, Flask, Docker, AWS, Metabase
- Developed a machine learning model for our eCommerce part manufacturing business, progressing from ad hoc statistical data exploration to production deployment, to instantly generate customer quotes for the FDM 3D printing process

• runtastic Linz, Austria
Data Engineer Oct 2018–Sep 2019

- Tech stack: Python, Spark, Hadoop, Flume, Oozie, Hive, RabbitMQ
- Led the design and deployment of a "People You Might Know" data product using Spark, scikitlearn, SparkML, and Elasticsearch
- Built a data exchange prototype with Kafka and a production system with AWS S3

• Allstate

Research Analyst

Menlo Park, CA

Jul 2016–Sep 2018

- Tech stack: Python, Pandas, Tensorflow, Spark, Julia, PostGIS
- Trained machine learning models and analyzed telematics and crash data for risk prediction
- Co-authored a paper on our research "Real-time Prediction of Intermediate-Horizon Automotive Collision" with the Stanford Intelligent Systems Lab

Education

• University of California, Santa Barbara
MS Mechanical Engineering

Santa Barbara, CA Dec 2014

- Tech stack: MATLAB, SolidWorks, I₄TĘX, TikZ
- Thesis research: Measured Faraday waves using a novel image processing technique for cheap 3D high-speed mm-resolution measurement over a surface area of 225 cm²
- University of California, Santa Barbara BS Physics & BS Mechanical Engineering

Santa Barbara, CA June 2010